<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Experimental Textiles</title>
    <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Experimental Textiles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Plan</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/lesson-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/lesson-plan/</guid>
      <description>Lesson Plan # Date Monday Date Wednesday 8/22 Class IntroSetting Community Norms, Questions about How Class Will Take Place, Paper Weaving Read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;Weaving, Hand&amp;rdquo;, pp 20-22 8/24 Design Philosophy &amp;amp; Documentation In Design Tutorial, How to Take Good Photos, Review Weeklies Templates, How to Find a Woven things &amp;ldquo;in the wild&amp;rdquo;. Begin First Weekly 8/29 Share/Critique Weekly 1 Introduction to Looms and Drafts Read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;The Loom&amp;rdquo;, pp 23-43 and images on pp 83-89 AND &amp;ldquo;Draft Notation&amp;rdquo; on pp 45-47 and images on pp 90-93 8/31 Make A Book Loom How to warp your loom and starting to play with structure, intro to primary structures Begin Weekly 2 9/5 Labor Day, No Class In preparation for wednesday, read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;The Fundamental Constructions&amp;rdquo;, pp 39-37 and images on 93-96 and skim Sharon Alderman, Mastering Weave Structure, chapters 1 (plain weave), 2 (twills), 3 (satin) 9/7 Share/Critique: Weekly 2Steven Frost will show you how to warp your Cricket Loom (Laura doing Weaving Demos at Ars Elecronica!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Syllabus # Instructor # Laura Devendorf
Assistant Professor, ATLAS Institute &amp;amp; Dept. of Information Science
laura.devendorf@colorado.edu
Responsible for grading, participation and course administration.
Office Hours: Sign Up at this Link
Location and Timing # In person Monday, Wednesday: 9:00am - 10:50am ENVD 234
Course Schedule # You may view a detailed course schedule on the Lesson Plan link
Course Materials # You may view a detailed list of the materials that will be required for you to purchase or available for you to check out on the Materials List</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material List</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/material-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/material-list/</guid>
      <description>Material List # While most equipment required for the class will be provided, we are asking students to purchase a few materials on their own, as they are ones we expect some might already own. After the first half of the class, each student will refine their direction and may need access to more specific equipment and supplies. In that case, we have created a &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for you to check out or take materials as they are required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
