<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experimental Textiles - Fall 2022 on Experimental Textiles</title>
    <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experimental Textiles - Fall 2022 on Experimental Textiles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 - Documentation Exploration</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</guid>
      <description>1. Documentation Exploration # Documentation is a critical part of this course and it is done best when you have a dedicated setup or space for documenting while you work. This week, consider where you will be working on projects for this class and explore several options for capturing and documentation (e.g. photography, video).
Your goal is to find the setup that offers you the most quality for least effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Plan</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/lesson-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/lesson-plan/</guid>
      <description>Lesson Plan # Date Monday Date Wednesday 8/22 Class IntroSetting Community Norms, Questions about How Class Will Take Place, Paper Weaving Read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;Weaving, Hand&amp;rdquo;, pp 20-22 8/24 Design Philosophy &amp;amp; Documentation In Design Tutorial, How to Take Good Photos, Review Weeklies Templates, How to Find a Woven things &amp;ldquo;in the wild&amp;rdquo;. Begin First Weekly 8/29 Share/Critique Weekly 1 Introduction to Looms and Drafts Read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;The Loom&amp;rdquo;, pp 23-43 and images on pp 83-89 AND &amp;ldquo;Draft Notation&amp;rdquo; on pp 45-47 and images on pp 90-93 8/31 Make A Book Loom How to warp your loom and starting to play with structure, intro to primary structures Begin Weekly 2 9/5 Labor Day, No Class In preparation for wednesday, read Annie Albers, On Weaving, &amp;ldquo;The Fundamental Constructions&amp;rdquo;, pp 39-37 and images on 93-96 and skim Sharon Alderman, Mastering Weave Structure, chapters 1 (plain weave), 2 (twills), 3 (satin) 9/7 Share/Critique: Weekly 2Steven Frost will show you how to warp your Cricket Loom (Laura doing Weaving Demos at Ars Elecronica!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Project</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/projects-assignments/midterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/projects-assignments/midterm/</guid>
      <description>Midterm Project: Follow the Materials # Your midterm project is to produce a swatch for a class swatch book that demonstrates some functionality, possibly something that you discovered in our earlier weeklies. We take inspiration in this assignment from the e-textiles swatch exchange, where practitioners develop small samples of a material outcome of a technique they developed and instructions for replication that are shared into a physical book with other practitioners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Syllabus # Instructor # Laura Devendorf
Assistant Professor, ATLAS Institute &amp;amp; Dept. of Information Science
laura.devendorf@colorado.edu
Responsible for grading, participation and course administration.
Office Hours: Sign Up at this Link
Location and Timing # In person Monday, Wednesday: 9:00am - 10:50am ENVD 234
Course Schedule # You may view a detailed course schedule on the Lesson Plan link
Course Materials # You may view a detailed list of the materials that will be required for you to purchase or available for you to check out on the Materials List</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - Make A Loom</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</guid>
      <description>2. Make a Loom # Watch this video: Repeat the process to make a loom with the following specifications. Your loom should have at least 20 ends/warps and use at least 2 colors. Weave two colors in any combination in the weft. Integrate at least 12&amp;quot; of conductive yarn or thread into the weave by any means you imagine. Weave something that relates to the contents of the book. Ask yourself, what else could you make a loom out of?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final - What If?</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/projects-assignments/final-project-adapt-to-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/projects-assignments/final-project-adapt-to-application/</guid>
      <description>Final Project: What If # Your final project will be a self-directed project, alone or in a pair, where you go deeper into one of the concepts or ideas learned earlier in the class. This might include:
Developing a new form of woven sensor or actor A deep dive into the possibility space of a given structure A contribution to the AdaCAD Code Base A reworking of a historic technique with new materials Your final project will be due and presented in the scheduled final time for this class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 - Warp and Weave</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</guid>
      <description>3. Warp and Weave # If you missed the in class warping, watch this video: Work with your partner to warp your cricket loom with 1 - 2 yards of cloth, 4-5 inches wide at 8 ends per inch.
While you are working on a shared loom, each student should weave 3, 3-4” sections that experiment with a different technique and weave 2 inches of a tabby between each section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material List</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/material-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/material-list/</guid>
      <description>Material List # While most equipment required for the class will be provided, we are asking students to purchase a few materials on their own, as they are ones we expect some might already own. After the first half of the class, each student will refine their direction and may need access to more specific equipment and supplies. In that case, we have created a &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; for you to check out or take materials as they are required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 - Dynamic Wefts</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</guid>
      <description>4. Dynamic Wefts # This week we will be rewarping and adding &amp;ldquo;frames&amp;rdquo; to our looms. Wind 2 yards of warp using a warping board or improvised method and then attach it to your loom. You should wind 40-50 warps using the 3/2 pearl cotton yarn provided in class. Use string heddles to create four frames in a straight draw.
Next, collect some materials to weave with that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t typically consider to be &amp;ldquo;yarn&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - Layer and Press</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-layer-and-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-layer-and-press/</guid>
      <description>5. Layer and Press # Use AdaCAD to design a multi-layer weave where the layers change order at one or more places in the structure. Weave and then create it on your loom and see if you can use it to create a press button by integrating a conductive yarn in the top and bottom layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 - Make Your Own Structure</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-make-your-own-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-make-your-own-structure/</guid>
      <description>6. Make Your Own Structure # Design your own structure in AdaCAD and weave it using your shared loom. Create at least 2 4&amp;quot;x4&amp;quot; structures using two different weft materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 - Reverse Drafting</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/7-reverse-drafting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/7-reverse-drafting/</guid>
      <description>7. Reverse Drafting # Take a swatch from those provided in class and study the structure by way of reverse drafting. Attept to create at draft of size 20 ends x 10 pics from the structure you have selected. What did you learn in this process? What new techniques emerged?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 - Investigating Fiber</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/8-investigating-fiber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/8-investigating-fiber/</guid>
      <description>8.Investigating Fiber # Pick a fiber, any fiber, although it cannot be one that we covered in class. Explore the properties of this fiber. Questions you need to answer: What are the properties of this fiber? What can it do? What can’t it do? Is this fiber a precious material or abundantly available? Where does it come from? What is its origin story? What might it be good for?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 - Jacquard</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/9-jacquard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/9-jacquard/</guid>
      <description>9. Jacuqard # Use AdaCAD to design a bitmap to &amp;ldquo;produce&amp;rdquo; using the Jacquard loom. The file must be 2360 pixels wide and no more than 100 pics. You are welcome to produce a sample blanket, image motif, or cloth. To use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/templates/in-class-critique-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/templates/in-class-critique-structure/</guid>
      <description>In Class Critique Structure # Each week, we will critique each other&amp;rsquo;s weeklies in a method that resembles Liz Lerman&amp;rsquo;s Critical Response Process. This process is used to help us guide a critique while still keeping the maker&amp;rsquo;s ideas, goals, and values central to the evaluation of the work.
First, we will quickly share our projects to the whole class, next, we will break into breakout groups of roughly 4 students each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/templates/weeklies-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/templates/weeklies-template/</guid>
      <description>Weeklies Template # Each weekly will give you a prompt and a technique to use. In your assignment turn turn in, you&amp;rsquo;ll will describe what you did. This template is about process. Process means the journey you follow when attempting an assignment, not just the ending point. All the things that you do that go well, inspire a next step, or go not as you planed and either cause you to change your direction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
