<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeklies on Experimental Textiles</title>
    <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeklies on Experimental Textiles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 - Documentation Exploration</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</guid>
      <description>1. Documentation Exploration # Documentation is a critical part of this course and it is done best when you have a dedicated setup or space for documenting while you work. This week, consider where you will be working on projects for this class and explore several options for capturing and documentation (e.g. photography, video).
Your goal is to find the setup that offers you the most quality for least effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - Make A Loom</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</guid>
      <description>2. Make a Loom # Watch this video: Repeat the process to make a loom with the following specifications. Your loom should have at least 20 ends/warps and use at least 2 colors. Weave two colors in any combination in the weft. Integrate at least 12&amp;quot; of conductive yarn or thread into the weave by any means you imagine. Weave something that relates to the contents of the book. Ask yourself, what else could you make a loom out of?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 - Warp and Weave</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</guid>
      <description>3. Warp and Weave # If you missed the in class warping, watch this video: Work with your partner to warp your cricket loom with 1 - 2 yards of cloth, 4-5 inches wide at 8 ends per inch.
While you are working on a shared loom, each student should weave 3, 3-4” sections that experiment with a different technique and weave 2 inches of a tabby between each section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 - Dynamic Wefts</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</guid>
      <description>4. Dynamic Wefts # This week we will be rewarping and adding &amp;ldquo;frames&amp;rdquo; to our looms. Wind 2 yards of warp using a warping board or improvised method and then attach it to your loom. You should wind 40-50 warps using the 3/2 pearl cotton yarn provided in class. Use string heddles to create four frames in a straight draw.
Next, collect some materials to weave with that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t typically consider to be &amp;ldquo;yarn&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - Embodying Weave Structure</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-embodying-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-embodying-structure/</guid>
      <description>5. Embodying Weave Structure # This weekly is a 2-week weekly that will consist of several parts. Complete the following:
Complete the reverse drafting worksheet with a swatch that will be provided to you in class. Follow each step on the worksheet carefully and make notes and comments about what you learned through this process in your weekly write up. Please bring your physical worksheet to class on Oct 10 for grading as part of this weekly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 - Jacquard</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-jacquard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-jacquard/</guid>
      <description>9. Designing for Jacquard # Use AdaCAD to design a bitmap to &amp;ldquo;produce&amp;rdquo; using the Jacquard loom. The file must be 2360 pixels wide and no more than 100 pics. You are welcome to produce a sample blanket, image motif, or cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
