<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeklies on Experimental Textiles</title>
    <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeklies on Experimental Textiles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 - Documentation Exploration</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/1-documentation-setup/</guid>
      <description>1. Documentation Exploration # Documentation is a critical part of this course and it is done best when you have a dedicated setup or space for documenting while you work. This week, consider where you will be working on projects for this class and explore several options for capturing and documentation (e.g. photography, video). Your goal is to find the setup that offers you the most quality for least effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - Make A Loom</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/2-make-a-loom/</guid>
      <description>2. Make a Loom # Watch this video: Repeat the process to make a loom with the following specifications. Your loom should have at least 20 ends/warps and use at least 2 colors. Weave two colors in any combination in the weft. Integrate at least 12&amp;quot; of conductive yarn or thread into the weave by any means you imagine. Weave something that relates to the contents of the book. Ask yourself, what else could you make a loom out of?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 - Warp and Weave</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/3-warp-and-weave/</guid>
      <description>3. Warp and Weave # Watch this video: Work with your partner to warp your loom with at least 5 yards of cloth, 4-5 inches wide. Create five shafts/harnesses and thread them using a straight draw. weave 1 3-4” section of any twill you choose, and another of any satin that you choose. Integrate 24” of conductive into each swatch and bring the swatches to class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 - Dynamic Wefts</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/4-dynamic-wefts/</guid>
      <description>4. Dynamic Wefts # This week, try to weave something other than &amp;ldquo;yarn&amp;rdquo;. Ideas include tubing, monofilament, shape memory alloys, paper, elatic or others you might think of. Create two swatches of at least 4&amp;quot;x4&amp;quot; that use different structures in the weft. Bring your swatches to class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - Layer and Press</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-layer-and-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/5-layer-and-press/</guid>
      <description>5. Layer and Press # Use AdaCAD to design a multi-layer weave where the layers change order at one or more places in the structure. Weave and then create it on your loom and see if you can use it to create a press button by integrating a conductive yarn in the top and bottom layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 - Make Your Own Structure</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-make-your-own-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/6-make-your-own-structure/</guid>
      <description>6. Make Your Own Structure # Design your own structure in AdaCAD and weave it using your shared loom. Create at least 2 4&amp;quot;x4&amp;quot; structures using two different weft materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 - Reverse Drafting</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/7-reverse-drafting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/7-reverse-drafting/</guid>
      <description>7. Reverse Drafting # Take a swatch from those provided in class and study the structure by way of reverse drafting. Attept to create at draft of size 20 ends x 10 pics from the structure you have selected. What did you learn in this process? What new techniques emerged?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 - Investigating Fiber</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/8-investigating-fiber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/8-investigating-fiber/</guid>
      <description>8.Investigating Fiber # Pick a fiber, any fiber, although it cannot be one that we covered in class. Explore the properties of this fiber. Questions you need to answer: What are the properties of this fiber? What can it do? What can’t it do? Is this fiber a precious material or abundantly available? Where does it come from? What is its origin story? What might it be good for?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 - Jacquard</title>
      <link>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/9-jacquard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://unstable.design/courses/experimental-textiles/docs/weeklies/9-jacquard/</guid>
      <description>9. Jacuqard # Use AdaCAD to design a bitmap to &amp;ldquo;produce&amp;rdquo; using the Jacquard loom. The file must be 2360 pixels wide and no more than 100 pics. You are welcome to produce a sample blanket, image motif, or cloth. To use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
